Gregory Siggins

Cherry Valley, CA

Phone: 408-661-3227 | Email: gregory.siggins@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/gregory-siggins/ | Portfolio: https://gsiggins.github.io/gsiggins-portfolio/

Summary

A Full-Stack Web developer who uses previous experience in paramedic-level emergency medicine to bring a detail-oriented, critical-thinking mindset to coding. Recently earned a certificate from the UCLA Extension Coding Bootcamp, with skills in the Mongo-Express-React-Node stack, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and object oriented programing. Known as a problem solver with a knack for JavaScript, coding has ignited a passion for developing concise and well documented code with a responsive and aesthetically pleasing user experience. Strong skills in teamwork and communication under challenging conditions and deadlines are just some of the skills that can benefit a professional development team. Prepared to bring a problem-solving drive to a fast-paced team who provides an intuitive, aesthetically pleasing, and user experience focused product.

Technical Skills

Languages

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Markdown

Database Techs

- Mongo
- Mongoose
- SQL
- Sequelize

Technologies

- React
- Bootstrap
- jQuery
- Tailwind
- Express
- Node.js

Projects

Down with the Fitness

Repo: https://github.com/MAMcCo/down-with-the-fitness Application: https://down-with-the-fitness.herokuapp.com/

- This app is a MERN application focused on fitness. It allows users to choose from a predefined list of workouts grouped by target area, or create and save their own workouts using a user-friendly modal.
- Responsible for front-end Javascript, React, and routing, including front-end UX.
- Javascript, HTML, CSS, Mongo/Mongoose, Express, React, Node.js

Popcorn Pal

Repo: https://github.com/GSiggins/bcs-2-app Application: https://enthousiaste-croissant-93148.herokuapp.com/

- Using a pre-seeded database, users are able to see reviews for a specific theater's amenities such as parking, concessions, seating, etc. Users are also able to write and submit their own review of a theater.
- Responsible for Javascript and Database functionality, including front-end UX.
- Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Handlebars

Note Taker

Repo: https://github.com/GSiggins/note-buddy Application: https://vast-peak-19005.herokuapp.com/

- A simple front end application allowing users to take notes of lectures, meetings, etc. Allows users to recall previous notes, save new notes, and delete old notes as needed.
- Created the entire app using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Relevant Experience

Nuclear Imaging Technologist - Insight Diagnostics

Fresno, CA - 05/2020 - 12/2020

- Successfully performed 8-14 intensive medical procedures daily.
- Performed weekly inventory and resupply of 300+ medical items.
- Explained complicated procedures via clear communication to a wide variety of clients.
- Successfully navigated a diverse range of cultures, languages, and personalities.

Paramedic – Riggs Ambulance Service

Merced, CA - 06/2018 - 03/2020

- Led teams ranging from 2 to 10 personnel for over 2,000 individual 911 responses.
- Performed daily inventory of over 40 required medical items.
- Chosen for a multi-department tactical medical team through merit and testing.
- Coordinated with leadership of over 8 agencies including local, state, and federal level.

EMT – B – Royal Ambulance

Santa Clara, CA - 07/2014 - 01/2016

- Worked as a part of a critical care team providing multi-disciplined care with shared goals.
- Facilitated comprehensive and individualized care to patients.
- Provided mobile medical transports safely and in accordance with California's Code of Regulations.

Education

Coding Bootcamp Certificate: UCLA Extension, Los Angeles, CA Graduated: 08/22

An intensive 12 week coding bootcamp focusing on full-stack web development culminating in a MERN application

Paramedicine: WestMed University, Santa Clara, CA Graduated: 02/18

Vocational degree in paramedicine. Strong focus in communication, teamwork, problem solving, and critical thinking.

Emergency Medical Technician: UCLA Extension, Los Angeles, CA Graduated: 04/14